希望是一种强大的东西
Hope is a powerful thing.
梅兰妮用它来团结人民
Melanie used it to unite the people,
先是用一个谎言
first with a lie,
然后承诺在雪国列车上的生活
but then with the promise of a life off of Snowpiercer.
安德烈·莱顿用希望来激励他的人民
Andre Layton used hope to inspire his people,
争取自由
to fight for their freedom,
但看看他的下场
but look where that's got him.
而威尔福德先生就不一样了
And Mr. Wilford is a different story.
他把希望变为恐惧
He's turned hope into fear.
他让列车叛变
He's turned the train against itself
然后提出保护
and then offered security.
有趣的是  在他接管以后
The funny thing is, since he took control,
一切似乎运行得都很顺利
everything appears to be running smoothly.
人人都参与工作
Everyone is showing up for work.
补给线井然有序
The supply lines are a picture of order.
但我们已经体验过了
But we've been here before.
把那些递过来
Hey, hand those over.
快  快点  快
Come on, let's move. Let's go.
我自己的希望被我藏着
My own hope I keep hidden.
该走了
Time to go.
藏在为数不多几个能重新将其点燃的人手里
Hidden in the few people who can rekindle it.
我没有关于罗切和他家人的消息
I've got nothing more on Roche or his family.
装上货就快走  快
Hey, load up and move! Let's go.
威尔福德找我
Wilford sent for me.
你最好进来
You better come inside.
你还好吗
You all right?
有我们在后车朋友的消息吗
Any message from our friends downtrain?
他们的信息都是一样的
They have the same info,
安德烈在大爱丽丝化粪室
that Andre's in Big Alice Compost.
他们称其为沼泽
They call it the Swamp.
知道威尔福德找我干什么吗
Any idea what Wilford wants from me?
-我尽量去打听  -好
- I'll try and find out. - Okay.
他让我忙着策划一个特别之夜
He's got me up to my eyeballs planning a special evening.
好朋友奥德丽多半跟他说了我们的情况
Good friend Audrey probably told them all about us.
不敢相信她信了他的花言巧语
I can't believe she fell for his shit.
至少她知道她不该露面
At least she's got the sense not to show her face.
听着  要想在威尔福德先生的统治下幸存
Look, the way to survive Mr. Wilford,
你就得对他有作用
you just gotta be something that he needs.
你保持斗志
You keep your chin up.
遵命
Yes, ma'am.
威尔福德先生的秩序
Mr. Wilford's order
代价很高
comes at a very high price.
我知道有坏事将要发生
And I just know that something awful is coming.
在雪国列车上  1034节车厢
On Snowpiercer, 1,034 cars long.
雪国列车
第二季 第九集
"继续上演"
今晚的活动准备得怎么样了
How are the evening's festivities coming on?
在计划时间内  先生
Right on schedule, sir.
我能问下  有宾客名单吗
Might I ask-- is there a guest list?
有的
Ah, yes.
随机赢家  那是凯文的领域
Random winners, that's Kevin's domain.
他负责今天的一个特别惊喜
He's in charge of a special surprise today.
什么样的惊喜
Oh, what kind of surprise?
给整辆列车准备的
One for the whole train
庆祝合法的领袖
to celebrate rightful leadership.
你休息下吧  露丝
Take some time off, Ruth,
这样你也能好好享受下
so you can enjoy some of it too,
但首先我要给你俩安排一项任务
but first I have a job for the both of you.
我俩一起吗  先生
Both of us, sir, together?
雪国列车变模糊了
Snowpiercer's getting muddy,
所有阶级都混在一起
all the classes mixed up and down.
真是一团乱
What a mess.
你们要开始一次完整的人口普查
Well, you ought to begin a full census.
我想要乘客像过去那样有组织
I want the passengers organized like in the old days.
我想知道谁在哪  在干什么
I want to know who is where doing what.
-遵命  -遵命
- Yes, sir. - Yes, sir.
他会改变一切
He'll change everything around now.
威尔福德想要适应力  我讨厌这词
Wilford wants resiliency. I hate that word.
他想要我们分开
He wants to keep us apart.
记住  他们会监听
Remember, they're gonna be monitoring
我们在火车头之间的所有交流
everything we say between the Engines.
-你会没事的  -到什么时候
- You're gonna be okay. - Yeah, until when?
万一他把我关进沼泽呢
What if he throws me in the Swamp?
他在一个接一个地除掉我们
He's picking us off one by one.
他不能再失去工程师了
He can't afford to lose another Engineer.
-跟总部报告  -嗯
- Check in with HQ? - Yeah.
我需要你保持火车前进
I need you to keep pushing this train forward.
我们离接梅兰妮就剩一周了
We're a week away from picking Melanie up.
-如果她在那的话  -她会在的
- Yeah, if she's there. - She'll be there.
我们已经晚了一天
We're already a day late.
我们在一周多前就失去了和她的联系
We lost contact with her over a week ago.
但威尔福德不知道  对吗
But Wilford doesn't know that, does he?
保持这样
Well, keep it that way.
安全让她回家  这就是任务  别问问题
Get her home safe. That's the mission. No questions.
-好  -快点  该走了
- All right. - Come on, let's go.
你也跟我来
Y tú...vienes conmigo.
惊喜是什么  凯文
What's the big surprise, Kevin?
我们越快开始普查  你就越早能知道
The sooner we get the census going, the sooner you'll find out.
拜托  我知道你迫不及待想要告诉我
Oh, come on, I know you're dying to tell me.
抱歉  发誓要保密
Sorry, sworn to secrecy.
-你了解他的  -嗯
- You know how he is. - Mm-hmm.
这些是什么
What is all of this?
病人病历
Patients' Records.
从我的诊所里拿出来的
Took 'em right out of my clinic.
这些不是乘客档案
These are not passenger files.
-这些是病历  -应该是保密的
- These are medical records. - Supposed to be confidential.
他想要按年龄把他们分开
He wants them divided by age--
小孩  青少年  18-39岁的  其余都算老人
children, adolescents, 18 to 39. The rest, elderly.
老人
Elderly?
我的天
Dear me.
这些是为了什么  凯文
What's all this in aid of, Kevin?
我猜他想要看谁适合做什么
I guess he wants to see who's fit for what.
每个乘客都要填写一份抽样调查问卷
A sample questionnaire for each of the passengers to fill out.
你是无票乘客吗
"Are you an un-ticketed passenger?
你知道跟反叛军一起作战过的任何乘客吗
Are you aware of any passengers who fought with the rebels?"
这是为了存档  一个历史记录
Well, it's for the archives-- a matter of historical record.
但我会告诉他你不满意
I'll tell him you're displeased, though.
不  凯文  你不能
No, Kevin, you won't.
我会亲自和威尔福德先生谈话  谢谢
I'll have my own conversations with Mr. Wilford, thank you very much.
我认识这车上的每个乘客
I know every passenger on this train,
我认为我对他们每个人都负有责任
and I consider myself responsible for each of them.
真扫兴
How unpleasant.
我关心这些乘客  凯文  这是警告
I care about these passengers, Kevin. That's a warning.
我们明天拿调查问卷给你
We'll be back tomorrow for your questionnaires.
快点走
Hey, keep moving.
-艾莉克斯  -我知道
- Alex. - I know.
我是哈维尔  哈维
I'm Javier--Javi.
第五位工程师  坐
Fifth Engineer. Sit.
没有我的允许请不要碰任何东西
Please don't touch anything unless I tell you to.
-那个仪表盘是新的  -不是新的  翻修过了
- That panel's new, no? - It's not new. It's overhauled.
我在第二圈的时候更新了界面
I upgraded the interface on the second revolution.
请别碰任何东西
Please don't touch anything.
这是雪国列车上的
It's from Snowpiercer.
其实是一个你妈妈的笑话
It's actually a joke from your mom.
我们在那边放了很多年  我以为你会喜欢
We had it out there for years. I thought you'd like it.
少拍我马屁
Don't butter me up, okay?
威尔福德让你做工程师  你就做好你的本职
Wilford tapped you as an Engineer. You're gonna stick to that.
你知道
You know...
你妈从这回去的时候
when your mom came back from here,
她说你不只是在技术方面很厉害
she said you weren't just technically good.
她说你有自己的风格
She said you had the touch.
那你有自己的风格吗
Well, do you have the touch?
还好了  不如你妈妈
Mas o menos. Not like your mom.
让列车平稳行驶就是了
Just keep us on the track.
-好  你要去哪  -前车
- Ok--where are you going? - Uptrain.
今天是雪国列车的大日子  很遗憾你没被邀请
It's a big day on Snowpiercer. I'm sorry you're not invited.
我从大爱丽丝带来的  是我的最爱之一
Brought her up from Big Alice, one of my favorites.
你看到尸体纠缠在一起了吗
You see how the bodies are entwined?
分辨不出他们究竟是在打架还是...  你懂的
Can't tell whether they're fighting or... Well, you know.
你有什么想法  贝丝·提尔
What do you think, Bess Till?
我认为许多乘客都感到担忧
I think a lot of the passengers are concerned.
不断有人失踪
People keep disappearing.
莱顿  现在是司闸员罗切和他的家人
Layton and now Brakeman Roche and his family.
你这人好打听
You're a curious creature.
我不知道该拿你怎么办
I don't know what to do with you.
维修队有八个人被谋杀
Eight of our Breachmen murdered,
我可以...找到凶手
I could...find the killers,
结案
close the case.
"列车警探"是梅兰妮发明的职务
You see, "Train Detective" is a Melanie invention.
我从来都不需要
I never needed one.
-你知道为什么吗  -不  先生
- You know why? - No, sir.
因为以前我的列车上没有犯罪
Because there wasn't any crime on my train.
现在也没有犯罪  只有秩序
There is no crime, only order.
你应该没那么天真吧
I don't think you're that naive.
你应该也没那么无辜吧
And I don't think you're that innocent.
好吧
Very well.
你可以告诉乘客罗切先生进了抽屉
You can tell the passengers Mr. Roche is in a Drawer
和他的家人一起
along with his family.
等你们都安定下来  他们就可以回来
When you all settle down, they can rejoin us.
-那会引起人们哗然  -我知道
- That won't go over well. - I know.
但我正好有让大家振奋的东西
But I have just the tonic.
赛克斯  带她到272车厢
Sikes, take her down to car 272.
不用担心莱顿先生
And don't worry about Mr. Layton.
我们让他宾至如归
We've made him quite at home.
现在我知道你们只是在服从威尔福德的命令
Now I know you're just following Wilford's order,
但我有权知道你们对我做了什么
but I have a right to know what you've done to me.
你发现得太早了
You found out prematurely.
没错  我把手放进了冷锁处  却没被冻掉
Yeah, I put my hand in the cold lock, and it didn't fall off.
他对我到底有何目的
What does he want with me?
拜托
Please.
你被送到我们这时
When you arrived with us--
你没必要给我看这个
You don't need to show me that.
每一秒我都经历过
I lived through every second of it.
我们把你修复好了
We repaired you.
是的  谢谢
Yes, thank you.
你们让痛苦消失了  但你们...
You took the pain away, but you...
未经我允许  就改造了我的身体
you have done something to my body without my consent!
-亲爱的  -乔茜
- Honey. - Josie...
你把手
what did it feel like
放进洞口时  是什么感觉
when you put your hand in the chamber?
你感到亢奋  对吗
It was a rush, wasn't it?
我没同意成为下一个冷淡鲍勃
I didn't sign up to be the next Icy Bob.
你比我们的鲍勃提高了好几个量级
You are orders of magnitude beyond our Bob.
你想知道更多吗  我们来看看可能性
You want to know more? Let's see what's possible.
老天  你能不能慢点  凯文
Oh, for Pete's sake, will you slow down, Kevin?
露丝  大惊喜就是这个
Ruth, this is the big surprise.
他要开启272车厢  并且委任我来管事
He's opening Car 272, and he's putting me in charge!
-272车厢已经关闭数年了  -等一下
- Car 272 has been closed for years. - Wait!
我需要个小孩
I need a kid.
过来
Come here.
快点
Come on.
快  我们走
Come on, let's go.
来  温妮  没事的  没事的
Come on, Winnie, it's all right. It's all right.
威利的世界
我的天呐
Oh, my goodness.
他马上就来  今晚即将盛大开幕
He'll be here in a jiff. Grand opening is tonight.
坐下  别乱跑
Sit. Stay.
那些不是给青少年玩的
Hey, hey, hey, those aren't for teenagers.
快把...  艾莉克斯  艾莉克斯
Come get--Alex. Alex.
别闹了  下来
Don't be ridiculous. Get down.
威尔福德把罗切和他的家人关进了抽屉
Wilford put Roche and his family in the Drawers.
罗切躺在抽屉里  哈维在大爱丽丝
Roche in the Drawer, Javi on Big Alice,
-莱顿在化粪室  -现在又来这闹剧
- and Layton's in his compost. - And now this shit show.
好了  开始了
Oh, oh, okay, here it comes.
技术排练即将开始
Tech rehearsal's starting.
所有人  上去
Everybody, up, up, up.
太棒了
Bravo.
-闪亮登场啊  -威尔福德先生
- What an entrance! - Mr. Wilford!
好极了  刚才真的很棒
Wonderful, that was really good.
-时机完美  太了不起了  -对
- Perfect timing. It's marvelous, isn't it, eh? - Yeah.
不喜欢这个  去掉
Don't like that. Get rid of it.
木偶师在舞台排成一排
Line the stage for the puppeteers.
就是这样  来啊
There we go. Come along.
看见没  都聚在一起
You see this? Gather 'round.
特别预演
Special preview--
为各位献上史诗传奇
an epic saga for the masses.
-祝好运  -谢谢
- Good luck. - Thank you.
谢谢您  先生
Thank you, sir.
我心爱的雪国列车
At last, my beloved Snowpiercer
和我想念的所有人终于重聚了
and all of the people I've missed.
我很快就会见到我妈妈
Soon I'm gonna see my Mama!
太棒了  威尔福德
Whee, Wilford!
我是首席工程师梅兰妮
I'm Head Engineer Melanie.
我会证明冷其实是热
I will prove that cold is hot!
我要爬上那座冰冻的山
I'm going to climb that frozen mountain
放出一个气球
and send a balloon.
没有我们他们都疯了
They've gone mad without us.
-观察  -别去  妈妈  别去
- Observe. - Don't go, Mama! Don't go!
这不好笑
This isn't funny.
别担心  你们在我的列车上很安全
Don't worry. You're all safe on my train.
永动机永不停息
The Engine will provide.
我死了
I'm dead.
威尔福德
Wilford.
永动机永不停息  永动机永不停息
The Engine will provide. The Engine will provide.
太精彩了
Bravo, bravo.
确实精彩  你喜欢吗
Bravo indeed. Did you like that?
-喜欢  -很棒  对吗
- Yeah. - It was good, wasn't it?
别这样啊  你们都是怎么了
Oh, come on. What's wrong with you all?
骗子
Liar!
真是可悲的尝试
What a pathetic attempt.
你不能用这宣传方式杀死梅兰妮
You can't kill Melanie with this propaganda.
我们没有多余的时间  已经晚了一天了
We don't have extra time. We're already a day late.
你似乎没留心看结尾  艾莉克斯
I don't think you paid close enough attention to the ending, Alex.
我看了一眼
I got a peek at the launch data
你精心篡改的发射数据
that you so carefully doctored.
本十天前就和梅兰妮失联了
Ben lost contact with Melanie ten days ago.
真的吗
You did?
在发射即将结束时  是的
Towards the end of the launches, yes,
我们失联了  但梅兰妮能挺过难关
we lost contact, but Melanie is a survivor,
她接收到的数据足够她建立气候模型
and she received enough data to complete a climate model.
好了  回火车头
All right, all right, back to the Engine.
别放弃她  艾莉克斯
Don't give up on her, Alex.
露丝  护送他们去前面
Ruth, escort them forward.
你还要为我的晚会做准备
You have my evening to prepare.
恕我直言  你可以把莱顿关起来
With respect, you can go ahead and lock up Layton,
但你会发现在我们所有人身上都有他的斗志
but you'll find a bit of his fight in all of us now.
今晚为少数人举办的私人活动
Private event this evening for a very select few.
谢谢
Thank you.
我可以把男朋友也带过去吗
Could I also bring my boyfriend?
他是清洁部主管
He's the head of Janitorial.
可以
Yes.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢你  凯文
Thank you, Kevin.
把你的建议放在打扮参加宴会上吧
Dress your next advice in evening wear.
给
Here you go.
大家精神点
Everybody, look sharp.
威尔福德先生很快就会来到嘉年华
Mr. Wilford will be through with the carnival soon,
然后真正的表演就要开始了
and then the real show begins.
这些是法国葡萄酒酒杯
Those are bordeaux glasses.
我们现在要喝的是加州葡萄酒
We're serving zinfandel.
天呐
Dear me.
跟着我说
Now repeat it back to me.
告诉我们的朋友
Tell our friends.
带个口信给乔茜  让她去化粪室找莱顿
Get a message to Josie to find Layton in Compost.
我们不能放弃梅兰妮
We're not giving up on Melanie
或是离开这辆列车的梦想
or our dream of getting off this train.
我们不能放弃
We're not giving up--
你想怎么样
What do you want?
狂欢节礼物
Compliments of the carnival.
还有呢
There's more.
晚餐邀请函
An invitation to dinner.
温妮  今晚等威尔福德忙的时候
Winnie, tonight when Wilford's busy,
乔茜必须要找到莱顿好吗
Josie has to find Layton, okay?
我们需要他的帮忙
We need his help.
调低一点
Take it down slowly.
-稳定下来  -不行
- Level off. - No.
再降一点
A little further.
靠着墙站
Against the wall!
在我梦里  你来找我
You come to me in my dreams, you know?
还挺吓人的
Rather spooky.
所以你还没把我的脑袋卡在舱门外面吗
Is that why you haven't stuck my head out a port yet?
问个诚实的问题
Honest question.
坚守你的理想
Hanging on to your ideals,
前车人们爱戴你
being beloved by your people uptrain,
你觉得这对最后的结果会有什么影响吗
do you think it makes the slightest difference in the end?
有的
Yeah, it does.
对我而言  我看不到会有什么影响
Well, for the life of me, I can't see how.
我想我肯定是有什么特别的问题
I suppose there must be something uniquely wrong with me.
你不特别  威尔福德
You're not unique, Wilford.
你就是个年长的白人列车独裁者
You're an old, white dictator with a train set.
就是像你这样脆弱又强大的人
Fragile, powerful men like you
当初把地球给冻住了
froze the Earth in the first place.
是的  这是公关问题
Yes, it's a PR problem in that regard.
我没落下你的东西吧
I haven't got any of your stuff left, have I?
那种正直的麝香味
That musky smell of integrity.
洗掉后  你的日子也就到头了
When that washes off, it's a wrap for you.
你总是有你的跟随者
You'll always have your little followers,
但大部分永远也不会如你希望的那样去爱你
but the majority will never love you like you want them to.
人民的意志  你是怎么忍受的
The will of the people-- how can you stand it?
每一个小分支
Every little faction.
政治权力的铁石心肠
The cold heart of political power
就是服从
is obedience.
就是这些理念让我们总是成为敌人
That shit right there is why we'll always be enemies.
我感觉好多了
Well, I feel better.
我要和你剩下的朋友在前车一起共进晚餐
I'm dining uptrain tonight with the last of your friends.
扎拉要做出一些决定
Zarah has some decisions to make.
那你现在感受到爱了吗
So are you feeling loved now?
清理他们的粪便
Up to your elbows in their shit.
你敞开的心扉  莱顿先生
Your open heart, Mr. Layton,
泄露了你的每一步
it telegraphs your every move.
天呐
My God.
大家各就各位  幸运赢家来了
Places, everybody. Lucky winners are here.
是的
Yes, ma'am.
-我的天  -不了  谢谢
- Holy crap. - No thanks.
我回来了
I'm back.
我早该知道的
Should have bloody known.
这是什么  露丝  最后的晚餐吗
What are we in for, Ruth, the last supper?
这一整天都是一场黑暗的展览
This whole day's one long dark display.
他和说这些邀请函给随机挑选出的客人
He told me the tickets were for random guests.
这是凯文给我的
Kevin dropped this on me
把我关了一天
after keeping me locked up
剥夺了我的所有舒适用品
all day for my comfort.
如果威尔福德威胁她的女儿
If Wilford threatens her baby,
我就用黄油刀杀了他
I'm gonna kill him with my butter knife.
好了  别激动
All right, take it easy.
我会尽可能地干预
I'll run interference as best I can.
欢迎各位
Right, everybody, welcome.
少数的幸运人
You lucky few.
当列车里的其余人在参加狂欢节时
While the rest of the train takes in the 当carnival,
幸运赢家可以与威尔福德先生
you winners get to enjoy a more intimate evening
共享一个更亲密的夜晚
with Mr. Wilford.
好吧
Yeah.
我浑身不自在  到底是要做什么
I'm a fish out of water, man. What's this all about?
不知道  但就像你母亲常和你说的
I don't know, but like your mother used to tell you,
-低调一点  -你们都吓到了
- keep your head on a swivel. - You guys are freaking out.
其实我超级兴奋
Right, I'm actually super excited.
那你呢  艾莉克斯  你也超级兴奋吗
What about you, Alex? Are you "Super excited"?
我想我们要完蛋了
I think we're all screwed.
天呐
Dear me.
当然了
Of course it is!
大家好
Hello, everybody!
该死的奥德丽
Bloody Audrey.
我只想站在这里  看着你们所有人
I just want to stand here and gaze upon you all.
下来吧  约瑟夫  没必要大吼大叫
Come down, Joseph. There's no need to bellow.
我喜欢一桌子的奇怪客人
I love an eccentric table of guests, don't you?
新老朋友坐在一起
Mix it up with old friends and new.
纵情享受几道吃一次少一次的美味佳肴
Indulge our palates with a few dwindling delicacies.
那不是邀请函吗  露丝
Isn't that the ticket, Ruth?
邀请函是你在负责  先生  和以往一样
You're in charge of tickets, sir, as it ever was.
-威利  -在
- Willy. - Yes?
你能给我弹一曲钢琴吗
Would you tickle the ivories for us?
来吧  何乐而不为
Go on then. Why not?
她戴的是王冠吗
Is she wearing a freaking tiara?
不要脸
Shameless.
*阳光午后*
*On a sunny afternoon*
*携手爱人*
*With one you love*
*星空高挂*
*The stars above*
*等待夜幕*
*Waiting for the moon*
*奏响风琴*
*The old accordion playing*
*多愁善感*
*A sentimental
-*歌曲*  -*小曲*
- *Song* - *Tune*
是小曲  不是一首歌
It's a tune, not a song!
凯文
Kevin.
*漫步河边*
*Cruising down the river
你有你的狂欢节  这里是我的地盘
You've had your carnival. This is my room.
请去休息室待着
Please stay in the lounge.
好吧  他就交给你了
Fine, he's all yours.
*漫步河边*
*Down the river
*阳光午后*
*On a sunny afternoon
真是太美好了
Well, isn't this lovely?
我应该撤走这些餐具吗  先生
Shall I clear this setting, sir?
不  露丝
No, Ruth.
还有一个宾客
There's one last guest.
小莱拉
Lilah Junior.
当然  我认识你父母
Of course, I knew your parents.
你我是第一次见  奥斯维勒先生
You're new to me, Mr. Osweiller.
你们俩应该互相认识
And I believe you two know each other.
以前是司闸员搭档
Ex-Brakeman partners.
-没错  先生  -嗯
- That's correct, sir. - Yeah.
真有意思
That's fascinating.
不过艾莉克斯  你应该没见过扎拉吧
Oh, but Alex, I don't think you've met Zarah.
-她是乘客服务部的  -也是安德烈·莱顿的伴侣
- She's with Hospitality. - Also Andre Layton's partner.
-很高兴认识你  艾莉克斯  -幸会
- It's nice to meet you, Alex. - Nice to meet you.
前妻  对吗  奥德丽
Ex-wife, wasn't it, Audrey?
车尾离婚  也算数吧  对吗
a Tail divorce. It sort of counts, doesn't it?
在夜车里待了那么多年
All those years in the Nightcar...
我们告诉你的那些私事
all those personal things that we told you.
那是她的使命  帮我们敞开心扉和哀悼
It was her calling, helping us open up and grieve.
是啊  好让她可以像妓女一样出卖我们的秘密
Yeah, so she could sell our secrets like a whore.
好了  好了
Now, now, now, now.
莱顿先生怎么说的  我们是一辆列车
What did Mr. Layton say? We're all one train together.
没错
Exactly.
我想着吃顿晚餐
I thought dinner would be a nice way
能让我们再次团聚
to bring us all together again.
在上帝和奥德丽的指引下  列车一心
One train under God and Audrey.
她不喜欢那个木偶秀
She didn't like the puppet show.
是吗  我觉得很好笑啊
Really? 'Cause I thought it was hilarious.
-真的吗  -嗯
- Did you? Yeah? - Yeah.
梅兰妮没有这里的人
I mean, Melanie's not as pure as everyone
-想象中那么纯洁  -小莱
- around here thinks she is. - LJ.
我觉得威尔福德先生今晚
I think Mr. Wilford's heard enough
已经听了够多关于梅兰妮的事了  小莱
about Melanie for one night, LJ.
我没有
I haven't.
我想再听听关于我妈妈的谎言  莱拉
I would love to hear more lies about my mother, Lilah.
她是骗子
Well, she was the liar.
她想成为你
She wanted to be you.
她指控我犯罪
She accused me of a crime,
然后我发现了她的小秘密
and I found out her little secret,
所以她不得不推翻判决结果
so she had to overturn the verdict.
我困惑了  小莱
I'm puzzled, LJ.
如果梅兰妮推翻了判决结果
If Melanie overturned the verdict,
是不是就是说你确实有罪
does that mean you were guilty?
我
I, uh...
不
no, um...
所以你没有像我在文献里读到的那样
So you did not cut off those men's penises
割掉那些男人的阴茎吗
like I read about in the transcript?
我真是松了口气
I am so relieved.
这是真的吗  莱拉
Is that true, Lilah?
小莱是个好人  威尔福德先生
Lilah Junior is a good person, Mr. Wilford.
-是的  -她父母去世后她的生活跌入谷底
- Oh, yes. - She fell a long way from First when her parents passed.
她学会了工作  先生
She learned to work, sir.
她现在对列车很了解  我为她骄傲
She knows the train now, and I'm proud of her.
他会说话啊
He speaks.
来自东密德兰的奥斯维勒
Osweiller from the East Midlands.
你比你搭档还安静
You're even quieter than your partner,
可靠提尔
Trusty Till,
不过更浪漫
though a little more romantic, huh?
我对小莱的感情是真诚的
My intentions with Lilah Junior are sound, sir.
真感人  你听到了吗  奥德丽
How lovely. Did you hear that, Audrey?
听到了  他是真心的
Yeah, and he meant it.
告诉我  奥斯维勒先生  我之前的卫生主管  特伦斯
Tell me, Mr. Osweiller, my previous head of Janitorial, Terence,
他当初在我纽约的房子里任职
I brought from my buildings in New York.
你是怎么接替他位置的
How did you come to be in his shoes?
先生  之前是段混乱时期
Sir, those were chaotic times.
我们失去了很多人
We lost a lot of people in the troubles.
我们尽最大努力填补空缺
We've tried to fill in as best we could.
这问题很简单  一个擅离职守的司闸员
A simple question for an AWOL Brakeman
以及一个用叉子挖掉她父亲眼睛的女孩
and a girl who put out her father's eye with a fork.
仔细考虑下  奥斯维勒先生
Think very carefully about this, Mr. Osweiller.
我为什么要留着你
Why should I keep you?
回到我  孩子
Answer me, boy.
我能去弹奏一曲吗
May I?
小奥  你在干什么
Os, what are you doing?
-他会弹吗  -不知道
- Does he play? - I have no idea.
有段时间没弹过了  请见谅
It's been a while, if you'll forgive me...
大冰封后就没弹过
Not since the freeze.
*这是我写给你的冬季情歌*
*This is my winter song to you *
*风暴即将来袭*
* The storm is coming soon *
*它已在海面翻滚*
* It rolls in from the sea *
*我的声音如夜晚中的烽火*
* My voice a beacon in the night *
*我的话语会成为你的光亮*
* My words will be your light *
*带你找到我*
* To carry you to me *
*爱还活着吗*
* Is love alive? *
*这是我写给你的冬季情歌*
* This is my winter song *
*12月从没感觉如此不堪*
* December never felt so wrong *
*因为你已不在属于你的地方*
* 'Cause you're not where you belong *
*在我的臂弯里*
* Inside my arms *
*爱还活着吗*
* Is love alive? *
莱顿
Layton.
乔茜
Josie.
Josie?
稍等
One minute.
谢谢
Thank you.
乔茜  让我看看你
Josie, let me see you.
你好多了
You're better.
别妄下定论
Yeah, jury's still out on that one.
他治好了你
He fixed you.
我们时间不多
We haven't got much time.
扎拉通过车尾联系了我
Zarah contacted me through The Tail.
她说他们还没放弃
She said that they haven't given up.
他们想知道下一步是什么
They want to know what the next move is.
莱顿
Layton.
记住我们在为什么抗争
Remember what we're fighting for.
列车上的生活
Life off train.
我可以尝试救你出去
I could try and get you out of here.
-你帮不了我  -别这样
- You can't help me. - Come on.
我们上次这样相见  我们发动了一场革命
The last time we met like this, we started a revolution.
他为你准备了计划
He has plans for you.
你得待在原地
You have to stay where you are.
我知道  我必须这样
I know. I--I need to.
我不知道我怎么了
I don't know what's happening to me.
感觉像是重生
It feels like-it's like being reborn.
还有希望  对吗
There is still hope, isn't there?
你会找到你的时刻  我也会的
You'll find your moment. So will I.
保持对他人的信心  我们仍在一起
Keep faith in the others. We're still together.
时间到了
Time's up.
-够了  -谢谢
- That's enough. - Thank you.
告诉他们我们会完成我们开启的事
Tell them we'll finish what we started.
你有对手了  奥德丽
You have competition, Audrey.
是啊  挺好的  很不错
yeah, no, it was good. It's great.
非常棒
Bravo.
还有人想唱歌吗  扎拉
Anyone else wanna sing? Zarah?
不了  我不再会为了我的晚餐而唱歌
No, thanks. I'm done singing for my supper.
她会唱的  她是个幸存者
she'll sing. She's a survivor.
来吧  露丝
Join us, Ruth.
我有些事要告诉你
I have something to tell you.
小心点  露丝  他的话一个字都别信
Be careful, Ruth. Don't trust anything he says.
什么
Sorry?
你认识我妈妈  而他在试图
You knew my mom. Well, he's trying
让全车人反对回去接我妈妈
to turn the train against going back for her.
看在上帝的份上
for pity's sake.
我为木偶戏的事感到抱歉
I'm sorry about the bloody puppets.
她在轨道旁等着我们
She's waiting trackside, and we have
-我们必须要完成任务  -不
- to complete this mission! - No!
我已经不准备冒险带着
I'm no longer prepared
我们的两列火车再穿过那个山口了
to risk us taking two trains across that pass.
你弄清楚人口普查是为什么了吗
Have you figured out what the census is for yet?
你快弄清楚了吗
Are you close?
是为了什么  威尔福德先生
What is it for? Mr. Wilford?
你为什么不告诉他们你在大爱丽丝上都做了什么
Why don't you tell them what you did on Big Alice?
-够了  -我们一开始有两百人
- That's enough! - There were 200 of us at first,
但是之后  当他发现我们要使用掉太多的资源时
but then when he realized what a drain of resources we were,
他就剔除了一半的人
we were, he culled half of us.
男人  女人  小孩  他杀了他们所有人
Men, women, children, he took their lives!
你怎么敢这么说
How dare you?
他们的灵魂在上  你怎么敢这么说
On their souls, how dare you
逼我再经历那件事
make me relive it?
-带她去禁闭室  -别担心  我在禁闭室待过
- Take her to the brig. - Don't worry. I've been there before.
露丝  他要来对付你了
Ruth, he's coming for you.
坐下  露丝
Sit down, Ruth.
你知道的  先生  乘客服务部永远不可以坐下
As you know, sir, Hospitality never sits.
瞎说  你整晚都在疑惑
Nonsense, you've been wondering
是谁要坐在那个位置
who that setting's for all night.
-是为你准备的  -我
- It's for you. - Me?
是的  今天都是为你准备的  露丝
Yes, today's all about you, Ruth.
坐下吧
Sit down.
凯文
Kevin.
我知道你在上面
I know you're up there.
下来吧  你这个淘气的小男孩
Come down, you naughty, little boy.
希望大家都玩得很开心
Hope we're all having a wonderful time.
露丝  我想感谢你准备了这么无懈可击的晚宴
Ruth, I want to thank you for an impeccable evening.
你超越了你自己
You've outdone yourself.
凯文  我的小伙子  你经历了太多
Kevin, my lad, you've come through so much,
你也成功的举办了一场惊艳的嘉年华
and you've put on an amazing carnival.
-是我的荣幸  先生  -坐下吧
- It's my honor, sir. - Sit down.
你知道现在乘客服务部人员供过于求
You understand there is a glut in Hospitality,
意味着  部门主管只能有一个
which means there's only room for one head of department.
这个位置是你的  露丝
Job's yours, Ruth.
我
I--oh--
闭嘴  凯文
Shut up, Kevin.
站在我身边吧  就像你以前一直想要的那样
By my side just like you always wanted.
你要做的就是向全列车广播
All you have to do is address the train,
正式通知他们
inform them officially
我们不会回去接梅兰妮了
we're not returning for Melanie.
我不能这么做
I can't do that.
你说什么
Beg your pardon?
我不会那么做
I won't do it.
你是在拒绝我的邀请吗
Are you rejecting my offer?
是的
Yes, I am.
把你的制服脱下来
Take off your Teals.
我承认  我在分辨道德上有障碍
I confess, I'm morally dyslexic.
有的时候我分不清对错
Sometimes I don't know right from wrong.
我花了些时间  但还是找到了适合你的位置
It took a while, but we found you a role.
我的顾问
My advisor.
我不确定我配得上这个职位
Not sure I'm the person for that.
瞎说  你完美契合
Nonsense, you're perfect.
你为自己考虑
You think for yourself.
你经常在重大的道德问题上挣扎
You struggle with the big moral questions--
自由  正义
freedom, justice.
你可以告诉我  我哪里错了
You can show me where I'm going wrong,
-告诉我底线在哪  -你说的是什么底线
- show me the line. - And which line is that?
你先请
After you.
这些是杀了维修队的人
Your Breachmen's killers.
我想给你  你之前要求的
I wanted to give you what you asked for,
一个结案的机会
a chance to close the case.
他们非常愿意执行我的命令
They were only too happy to carry out my orders.
你只要说那个词  只要拉一下杠杆
Just say the word, and one pull of the lever
就可以通过冰肺来执行正义
will deliver justice by lung of ice.
这不是正义  正义需要公平的审判
This isn't justice. Justice requires a fair trial.
是吗
Does it?
不仅仅是下个裁决吗
Not just a verdict?
他们是按你的命令行事
They were acting on your behalf.
人人都是
Well, everyone does.
这只不过是  把他们都收拾掉
This just...tidies it all up.
先生
Sir
我建议你不要这么做
I advise you not to.
如果这是你的劝谏的话  那么好吧
Well, if that's your council, then fine.
你可以走了
You may go.
我不认为你会喜欢看最后这一小部分的
I don't think you're gonna want to watch the last bit.
靠墙站好
Against the wall!
这都是什么啊
What fresh hell is this?
他会告诉所有人她死了
He's gonna tell everyone that she's dead.
他知道我们和她失去了联系
He knows that we lost contact.
他不会回去接她的
He's not gonna go back for her.
他只会把她丢在外面  让她自生自灭
He's just gonna leave her out there on her own to die,
而我们会死在这里
and we are gonna die in here.
我从不认为你是个半途而废的人  露丝
Never had you down as a quitter, Ruth.
威尔福德有的只是恐惧
All Wilford's got is fear.
我们有的比他多得多
We got so much more than that--
我们有支持我们的朋友
friends who got our back,
那就是我们的力量所在
that is our strength.
雪国列车
Snowpiercer.
雪  雪国列车  听到请回答
Snow-- Snowpiercer, come in.
我现在应该在信号范围内了
I should be range now.
你收到了吗  我是梅兰妮
Do you copy? It's Melanie.
你是个优秀的工程师
You're a fine Engineer.
谢谢你  先生
Thank you...sir.
我压钱打赌  你要比本好
Better than Ben for my money.
但是已经没有钱这个东西了
But there's no money anymore.
现在只剩下一件事要做了
There's only one thing left to acquire.
现在我们可以依靠的就是列车了  哈维尔
All we can depend upon is the train now, Javier.
好的  先生
Yes, sir.
先生  我可以用你的洗手间吗
Sir, may I use your restroom please?
可以
Yeah.
这是什么
Oh, what's this?
瞧瞧这个
Look at that.
无线电联系成功  梅兰妮还活着  哈维尔
安德烈
Andre.
是哈维写的
It's from Javi.
梅兰妮  她联系上我们了
Melanie, she made contact.
你准备好开始聊聊怎么离开这里了吗
You ready to start talking about getting out of here?